<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolios on CIC</title>
    <link>https://jailingineni.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolios on CIC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 16:54:54 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jailingineni.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Investments club integrating community involvement with financial awareness</title>
      <link>https://jailingineni.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/portfolio/bottle-mockup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 16:54:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jailingineni.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/portfolio/bottle-mockup/</guid>
      <description>Investments club integrating community involvement with financial awareness At 4:30 p.m. on Jan 17, new members of the Charitable Investments Club checked into a Zoom meeting and were introduced to the club’s history, purposes and basic procedures that come with membership. Club officers presented the topics in a slideshow, which was followed with Zoom thumbs up icons as reactions.
“Our club promotes communicative skills and collaborative decision making,” CHS junior club member Faheem Tippu said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CIC Donates 204 Pounds of Peanut Butter to Local Food Bank</title>
      <link>https://jailingineni.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/portfolio/ntfb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 16:54:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jailingineni.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/portfolio/ntfb/</guid>
      <description>The Coppell Charitable Investments Club donates 204 pounds of peanut butter to the North Texas Food Bank PLANO, Texas - On September 24th, the Coppell Charitable Investments Club donated approximately 204 pounds of peanut butter to the North Texas Food Bank. Listed on the North Texas Food Bank website as a ‘most needed’ item, the 68 three pound jars of peanut butter were purchased with the profits derived from the Coppell Charitable Investments Club Portfolio to keep shelves stocked for people who may need food because of the staggering levels of unemployment caused by the pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
