<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CIC</title>
    <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CIC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 12:29:40 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2021-06-25</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog55/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog55/</guid>
      <description>After a period of getting things set up, today we made our first trade as a club! We bought 5 shares of SNAP. In addition, we discussed potential call options for MSFT, AAPL, and DIS. These stocks all have good news surrounding them, and many analysts have given them positive buy ratings. After discussion, we were planning on purchasing an MSFT call option, but our Fidelity account would not let us due to some internal configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2021-05-04</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog54/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog54/</guid>
      <description>After a long delay, we have finally gained access to our Fidelity account. This is a huge moment for us as we will now be able to work with the analyst team to invest in the market and hopefully make a profit. Our meeting today revolved around planning the future of the club now that we have an account. If we invest properly, we may be able to attract the attention of possible donors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2021-03-22</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog53/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog53/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s meeting, we talked about future plans and navigating through this busy part of the year. We gave out tasks to each board member. These tasks included finishing the website, starting the development of a CIC Bullseye strategy for investing, and uploading more on Instagram. These tasks will be completed by the end of next week and we will be investing by that time as well. If our stock picks are right, we plan on donating in May and then again after summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2021-02-22</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog52/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog52/</guid>
      <description>The weekly meetings have been going as planned, and we are now into our fundraising phase. We have set up a PayPal account and have all of the paperwork set so that all donors will receive a tax exempt status for their donation. Today we also discussed the creation of our club video, which we will use to market our club to companies. Finally, we set up a meeting time (Saturday at 10 a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investments club integrating community involvement with financial awareness</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/portfolio/bottle-mockup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 16:54:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/portfolio/bottle-mockup/</guid>
      <description>Investments club integrating community involvement with financial awareness At 4:30 p.m. on Jan 17, new members of the Charitable Investments Club checked into a Zoom meeting and were introduced to the club’s history, purposes and basic procedures that come with membership. Club officers presented the topics in a slideshow, which was followed with Zoom thumbs up icons as reactions.
“Our club promotes communicative skills and collaborative decision making,” CHS junior club member Faheem Tippu said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2021-01-26</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog51/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog51/</guid>
      <description>Today we got our pictures taken by the Sidekick, which is our school newspaper. They are working on an article about our club and its achievements. This is a small step in the right direction as it allows us to raise public awareness about our club and what we are trying to do for the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2021-01-19</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog50/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog50/</guid>
      <description>Two events occurred today, we had our scheduled team meetings and had an introductory meeting with the new recruits. We will be bringing in ten new people into CIC, and we are excited to see what we can do together. As for the team meetings, we just checked on whether the teams completed their tasks, and they did so they will now be moving on to the next task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2021-01-07</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog48/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog48/</guid>
      <description>Today we continued our work on the bylaws and finished the most critical parts of the document. While it is a mundane task, this document will make us more legitimate as an organization and we will be able to act on a variety of opportunities. In addition to this, we planned for future meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-12-27</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog47/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog47/</guid>
      <description>Today was the weekly meeting in which we discussed each group&amp;rsquo;s tasks. The analyst team will be responsible for researching stocks while the marketing team will be focusing on recruiting new members. In addition to that, the donations team will be brainstorming different companies we can reach out to for funding. Not much has been going on during this month because everyone had semester exams and after that wanted to relax over the winter break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-12-20</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog46/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog46/</guid>
      <description>Today was the weekly meeting in which we discussed each group&amp;rsquo;s tasks. The analyst team will be responsible for reviewing the updated curriculum while the marketing team will be focusing on outreach. In addition to that, the donations team will be brainstorming different companies we can reach out to for funding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-12-13</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog45/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog45/</guid>
      <description>Today was the weekly meeting in which we discussed each group&amp;rsquo;s tasks. The analyst team will be responsible for updating the curriculum while the marketing team will be focusing on making new social media accounts for the club. In addition to that, the donations team will be brainstorming different companies we can reach out to for funding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-12-06</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog44/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog44/</guid>
      <description>Today was the weekly meeting in which we discussed each group&amp;rsquo;s tasks. The analyst team will be responsible for researching stocks and updating the curriculum while the marketing team will be focusing on outreach. In addition to that, the donations team will be brainstorming different companies we can reach out to for funding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-11-01</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog43/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog43/</guid>
      <description>We have completed the mid term report despite all of our busy schedules. There was also a club meeting today, in which we checked up on how each team was doing. They have all been getting work done, and we told them to establish a blog so that we know how much work they are doing on a weekly basis.
As for the club account, it is not doing so well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-10-18</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog42/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog42/</guid>
      <description>We had our official club meeting today and we delegated the tasks to each team (analyst, donations, and marketing). Other than that, not much has been going on and we have continued to work on the Wharton Business Competition. To be honest, many people have not done enough work and that may cost us in the long run. The mid term report is due on November 2, and no one has talked about it yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-10-11</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog41/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog41/</guid>
      <description>Today we met with our club teams (donations, marketing, and analyst) separately and told them about their roles and responsibilities within the club. We all agreed that the meetings should be separate because it will warrant higher attendance and attention. Just as we expected, almost everyone attended and we feel like they are all on board with what they will be doing in the next few months.
As for the Wharton Investment Competition, we will be having a meeting about that tomorrow in which we will formulate a short term investment strategy for our client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-10-08</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog40/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog40/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while. Not because we haven&amp;rsquo;t been working, and not because I haven&amp;rsquo;t wanted to update the blog, but just because a lot of work has been piling up around everyone. Anyway, these few past weeks have been eventful and we have gotten a lot done. First of all, the club members are now almost fully initiated and they will begin fundraising/analyzing stocks/marketing soon. As for the Wharton Business Competition, we made our first two investments, both in the technology sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-09-26</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog39/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog39/</guid>
      <description>Today we had a relatively long meeting (around one hour) where we discussed the Wharton Business Competition and finalized the press release for our club&amp;rsquo;s donation. We wanted today to be a full on strategy development day, but not every member of the board was present, so we were unable to fully develop our strategy for the Wharton competition. For this reason, we will be having another meeting tomorrow at around 6 p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-09-23</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog38/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog38/</guid>
      <description>For this whole month, we have all been invested in the training of our recruits. As a result, we did not have too many board meetings. However, the month was still eventful for us. We will be donating the two hundred pounds of peanut butter to the North Texas Foodbank tomorrow (Thursday) at around 3:50 p.m. Moreover, we have been registered for the Wharton Business Competition and Mr. Simpson is our advisor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-09-15</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog37/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog37/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a short time since we had an official meeting, but we have been busy all the same. Just this last weekend (Sunday), we taught Unit 2 or our curriculum, and I am pleased to say that it was a success. The topics we covered are difficult, but we are confident that every club member will be able to understand them, especially after they get some practice.
As for today, we discussed how we are going to donate the peanut butter that we got recently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CIC Donates 204 Pounds of Peanut Butter to Local Food Bank</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/portfolio/ntfb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 16:54:54 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/portfolio/ntfb/</guid>
      <description>The Coppell Charitable Investments Club donates 204 pounds of peanut butter to the North Texas Food Bank PLANO, Texas - On September 24th, the Coppell Charitable Investments Club donated approximately 204 pounds of peanut butter to the North Texas Food Bank. Listed on the North Texas Food Bank website as a ‘most needed’ item, the 68 three pound jars of peanut butter were purchased with the profits derived from the Coppell Charitable Investments Club Portfolio to keep shelves stocked for people who may need food because of the staggering levels of unemployment caused by the pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-09-06</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog36/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog36/</guid>
      <description>As of today, our month of learning has officially started! The plan is to take all of the new club members through around four meetings (each about an hour long) that will teach them all they need to know about the stock market. Today was the first meeting, and it was led by me (Aksh Tyagi) and Kavin Sampath (club founder).
The teaching process went smoothly and everyone understood the material, which is a good sign as the first week content was relatively easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-09-04</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog35/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog35/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps we were too optimistic. As of now, our account is down by about 200 dollars from what it was. That is not too bad, and we understand that there will be both up and down days. If the market constantly went up, then we would be in a utopian society, which simply does not exist.
Looking on the bright side, we are ready to make our first donation. It will be peanut butter and we will donate it to a local homeless shelter as planned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-09-02</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog34/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Victory belongs to the most persevering&amp;rdquo; - Napoleon Bonaparte.
Our account hit 4,000 dollars today. This is a huge milestone for us and it proves that anything can be accomplished. Even today, we were not expecting such gains, but it just happened. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s the things that take us by surprise that truly make our day a memorable one. And even more importantly, the success we garnered was done by us and us alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-08-30</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog33/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog33/</guid>
      <description>Today we had a small meeting in which we showed the club account to our newest members. We felt that it would serve as an important inspiration for them to pursue learning how to invest. Moreover, they were informed of the schedule for the next few months and when the training would begin (first Sunday of September).
After the meeting was over, something interesting happened. We got a text from a member of a different non profit whose name will not be mentioned because it hardly matters in the current state of things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-08-27</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog32/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog32/</guid>
      <description>There was no meeting today, but we did hit a major milestone. Today we hit 500 dollars in profit! This was mostly thanks to the BABA and Walmart calls, each of which went up by around 30 percent. At the moment, the account is boasting a 20 percent growth, which is double or almost triple what most people would consider average growth. We have come a long way from the MGM fiasco, and it feels good to be in profit and ready to donate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-08-26</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog31/</guid>
      <description>Today our account has reached around 430 dollars in profit, and we are ready to make our first donation. So, we discussed where we wanted our donation to go. At first, we were thinking about donating to the North Texas Food Bank, but after some discussion, decided against it as we feel like they aren&amp;rsquo;t in as much need as some other places.
It was because of this reason that we decided to donate it to a homeless shelter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-08-25</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog30/</guid>
      <description>Our account took a small hit today (nothing major, it is still at 3,000 dollars). Today&amp;rsquo;s meeting was so that we could decide on what to do in order to bring the account to 300 dollars in profit. And decide we did.
We have two plans of action: one is buying a call option for FAS (an ETF) and the other is investing in Xpeng (an electric car company that will IPO this Thursday).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-08-23</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog29/</guid>
      <description>Today was the big day! We presented to 18 kids who we picked to join our club. The presentation went well and we had an excellent turnout (18/21). This is just the beginning, but what a beginning it is!
The meeting took place at 5:00 pm and it was over zoom. We screen shared a slide show and presented for around 30 minutes and then took questions. To our surprise, there were no questions, which must mean that we did a good job of presenting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-08-22</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog28/</guid>
      <description>We had a relatively small meeting in which we simply went over the slideshow for tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s presentation. We split the presentation into different parts and everyone will cover a specific aspect of the club.
Moreover, the club sponsor may also be attending the meeting tomorrow, so we have to make sure that whatever we say is truthful and impresses him. All in all, we are all ready for tomorrow and will make sure that everyone feels proud to be a part of the Charitable Investments Club.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-08-21</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog27/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog27/</guid>
      <description>Big things are coming. Today our account hit 3,000 dollars and now posts a gain of around 8 percent. The reason for this is mostly due to the BABA (Alibaba) call (which was sold for a 30 percent gain) and our investment in Apple. The synergy of the growth found in these two investments skyrocketed our account to right around 3,000 dollars.
We have sold BABA and are going to hold Apple because we want a stake in whatever growth occurs when the Apple stock splits into four on August 31.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-08-18</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog26/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog26/</guid>
      <description>Walmart&amp;rsquo;s stock fell today so we thought it would be a good time to buy a call option. The reasoning behind this was that Walmart is an extremely large and stable company, so the stock was bound to go back up. Lo and behold, the stock went back up and we make around a 33 percent gain on our call.
No meeting was required to make this decision, we all just took a vote on it via Slack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-08-15</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog25/</guid>
      <description>These next few weeks are going to be difficult but as Billy Cox says: &amp;ldquo;Life&amp;rsquo;s greatest difficulties always happen right before life&amp;rsquo;s greatest breakthroughs.&amp;rdquo; We all certainly hope this is true in our case. In today&amp;rsquo;s meeting, we discussed two major topics. Number one was advertising for the club and who should join the club initially. Number two was curriculum and document planning.
As for advertising, we have already created a social media account but we believe that just having the account will not help in the long run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-08-08</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;When people throw stones at you, turn them into milestones&amp;rdquo; - Sachin Tendulkar (Indian cricketer)
In our case, the stone was MGM and the person was the market. MGM tanked our account and we thought it would never be able to recover. However, we held the stock and now it has helped us reach a major milestone. That milestone is that we are now out of loss and have fifty dollars of profit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-08-04</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog23/</guid>
      <description>The big deal today for our club was that we purchased our first option! We used what we learned in the last meeting to guide us to make a solid decision on buying an option. BABA (Alibaba) was the company that we bought the option for and we believe that it will make us a lot of money as BABA is considered to be the Amazon of China. China is a big market and if BABA mirrors Amazon&amp;rsquo;s exponential growth, then this could be a very good investment for us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-07-31</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog22/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog22/</guid>
      <description>Today we talked about two investing terms: calls and puts. It was very confusing but towards the end we started to understand. Basically, a call is a contract between a person and the market. It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that the contract for the call does not exist between any two people because contracts are bought and sold anonymously.
For a call, the seller is selling one hundred shares of a stock that he or she owns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-07-29</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog21/</guid>
      <description>Today we tried something new. Normally, our meetings have been led by Kavin (club leader), but today, he decided that from now on meetings can be led by different individuals, which we hope will help us with leadership skills for when we open the club up to new members. So, for today, Prabhav led the meeting in which we went through a few critical things for the club. On the investing side, we are still stuck because MGM is really limiting our buying options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-07-27</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog20/</guid>
      <description>Relatively short meeting today. We finalized our game plan for the next few days by deciding which stocks to sell and which ones to buy. Snapchat (SNAP) was a stock that we bought recently and at present it is slightly negative. We decided that we are going to sell SNAP right before the market closes today. That way, we won&amp;rsquo;t have to ride with it through earnings, which could be quite harmful to the stock seeing as ad revenue is a very volatile subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-07-20</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog19/</guid>
      <description>Earnings are coming up so we need to be prepared, and that is exactly what we did today. We looked at the companies that were having earnings this week and which companies&#39; stocks we could buy in order to make a profit. It was also important to know if we were going to buy the stock before they released their earnings or after it. Both options are valid in different scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-07-17</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog18/</guid>
      <description>Big meeting today. We outlined what we have to get done and what our near future will look like. As of now, our main goal is to get a fiscal sponsorship through an organization called Interact. They will provide us with some money and help us raise awareness for our club. Once we become partnered with them (and we are hopeful that we will), we will have an air of credibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Year a New Posibility</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/extra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/extra/</guid>
      <description>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit. Quas sit expedita, iusto repellendus cumque, officia architecto consequatur illo fuga eum sed ut autem eos voluptas. Nemo, a, rem! Atque quisquam aperiam eaque tenetur autem, soluta itaque omnis. Minus nesciunt, sint, animi
 Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit. Quas alias ut totam labore, rerum soluta harum vitae pariatur, optio, ad dolore, nihil eligendi nesciunt repellat esse provident sapiente. Repellendus, minus!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-07-15</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog17/</guid>
      <description>We may be seeing the light at the end of the tunnel. There was no meeting today, but our account has started to perform well once again. Our decision to buy ULTA paid off as today the stock jumped by around twenty dollars, giving our account a boost of around forty dollars. Moreover, MGM finally began to rise, giving our account another boost. Currently, the account is 200 dollars from breaking even.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-07-07</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog16/</guid>
      <description>Our account is still down, but now we have a plan. For the past few days, we have been working together to secure a loan of money from another account. We put around 700 extra dollars into our account to combat the effects MGM was having on it. At the moment, our account balance is at around $2,400. With the extra money, the goal of the account has now become reaching $3,000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-06-30</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog15/</guid>
      <description>Our account isn&amp;rsquo;t doing so great at the moment. At today&amp;rsquo;s market close, the account had hit 1800 dollars. Our main problem is coming from MGM because we have 75 shares of it and it has tanked in the last couple of weeks. This is probably due to COVID still being very prevalent in many major cities across the country. However, we all decided today that we would continue to wait on selling MGM because we still believe the stock can go up as the people will eventually start going back to casinos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-06-16</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog14/</guid>
      <description>As we continue to wait for a proper time to sell MGM, we have now shifted our attention to becoming fiscally sponsored. What that means is that we want to become sponsored by a non-profit organization that shares a goal similar to that of ours. Eventually, once the club gets large enough, we would like to become a non profit organization ourselves, but that a few months away. For now, we are looking at how to get a fiscal sponsor and any clubs that we can draw knowledge from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-06-15</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog13/</guid>
      <description>Two major things today. First, we looked at how to spread awareness for our club through the use of social media. Second, we talked about MGM, a casino stock that has caused our account to &amp;ldquo;lose&amp;rdquo; a lot of money. We believe that, while MGM may be doing bad for our account now, it will go up in the near future. Our belief is backed up by the fact that MGM is opening new casinos in early July, meaning that more people will engage in gambling, leading to a larger revenue and stock valuation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-06-08</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog12/</guid>
      <description>Shopify was a bust, but that&amp;rsquo;s okay because today we made two major moves that will ensure our account&amp;rsquo;s prosperity. The deal with Shopify was that we put in a trailing stop loss order, but somehow it executed way below our order, meaning that we lost a lot more money than we expected. At this point, however, we all understand that not every investment we make into the stock market will result in gains for the account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-06-05</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog11/</guid>
      <description>Today we bought a share of Shopify, making it the most expensive stock ever bought by the account. Coming in at around 730 dollars, we bought Shopify because we saw that the stock was down and that once it recovered, we would make money. Moreover, we put in what is known as a trailing stock loss order. That simply means that there is a price that we set, and at that price the stock will sell, no matter what.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-06-02</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog10/</guid>
      <description>Major milestone today. We have hit a 100 dollars in profit!!! This is very important to us all as it shows that what we are doing is right and that we can be successful in our endeavours to raise money for charity. The main driver behind this was the averaging down that we did for many of our stocks, including our most recent purchase (LABU). Averaging down allowed us to correct our mistakes and capitalize on the stock&amp;rsquo;s price lowering and rising back up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-05-25</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog9/</guid>
      <description>Today was our first meeting in a few weeks because we were all busy studying for our AP exams. Now with that out of the way, today we met to discuss future buys for our account. There were two main stocks that we viewed: Shopify and LABU (ETF). Everyone decided to not buy Shopify right away and instead voted to monitor it for the next few days. As for LABU, we purchased 6 shares of it because we believe that it will go up either tomorrow or in the next few days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-05-09</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog8/</guid>
      <description>The start of this week was a rough one as our account went down a lot due to pinterest, amd, and twitter all falling. However, we were determined to make the account go back up, so we used the practice of averaging down to make that happen. When the stock went down, we bought more of it in hopes that it would go up and that we would be able to make a profit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-04-30</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog7/</guid>
      <description>The market went down significantly. Our account was in the negative. This is a tough time, but we understood that we should not panic and that in time, the companies that we have invested in will rebound. We learned about something related to our loss: realized vs. unrealized. It is a concept in the stock market in which once an account takes a loss, it is only called realized once the owner of the account sells that stock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-04-29</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog6/</guid>
      <description>Today we all learned about a term that is very important in the stock market: the stop loss order. It is an order in which a stock will sell when it drops to a certain price (set by the owner of the account). It is easy to think about it as a sort of safety net. If someone has made money, then they can set a stock loss order so that they won&amp;rsquo;t lose the money that they gain if the stock starts dropping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-04-26</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog5/</guid>
      <description>As of today, our club has made around 40 dollars, which is definitely a major milestone for us. We all spent some time celebrating but then got back to work as it is important that we not get complacent during a time in which the market is so volatile. Today was another research day in which we created a watchlist and had each club member suggest a stock to look into.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-04-23</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog4/</guid>
      <description>We were all excited to learn that today, our account had made around twenty dollars! It may seem like a little, but to us, it is a big deal because it shows that our first investment as a club is a success. Moreover, we talked about potential buys for the club. Snapchat, Raytheon, Jetblue, and Microsoft were all some of the companies that were discussed. No final decisions were made, as we did not want to be too risky with our buys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-04-17</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog3/</guid>
      <description>Today was a very big milestone for our club as we made the purchase of our first stock! This month, the whole club was tasked with finding good stocks that we could use to kickstart the investing in our club. The final options were pinterest and starbucks. Pinterest looked good because they had been growing steadily in the past few years and had small liabilities with large assets. This meant that they would most likely be able to weather the storm that is coronavirus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-04-14</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog2/</guid>
      <description>As the world continues to navigate through the coronavirus crisis, we as the Charitable Investments Club decided to continue in our efforts to benefit the community. Today we held a meeting in which we discussed how to help in our community, when and how to invest, and what our website should look like. Firstly, and most importantly, we went in depth on things that we could do to better the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-02-17</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog1/</guid>
      <description>Today was our second official meeting and it was a good continuation to the first one as we all learned a lot. As for our major topic of the day, we all discussed the major drop in oil, which we believed to be an effect of the coronavirus. Moreover, all of the club members presented once again their picks for good stocks to potentially buy. This created what may become a club tradition, in which each meeting, club members will all present stocks that they believe to be financially beneficial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on 2020-01-27</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog0/</guid>
      <description>Today was our first official meeting for the charitable investments club. There had been a few meetings prior to this one, but this was the meeting that we decided would be the first official one in our club history. During the meeting, we discussed many important topics like how to move the club forward, but more importantly, what was going on in the world at the time. We all talked about the death of Kobe Bryant and about how coronavirus was ravaging China.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Year a New Posibility</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/a-new-year-a-new-posibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/a-new-year-a-new-posibility/</guid>
      <description>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit. Quas sit expedita, iusto repellendus cumque, officia architecto consequatur illo fuga eum sed ut autem eos voluptas. Nemo, a, rem! Atque quisquam aperiam eaque tenetur autem, soluta itaque omnis. Minus nesciunt, sint, animi illum quo ab voluptate esse delectus unde maiores iure, quasi a suscipit ipsam aliquid voluptatem. Perspiciatis eveniet, pariatur illum aut cum dolor neque consequatur error aliquid facilis in quasi temporibus assumenda tempore, doloremque autem saepe enim nihil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Online Audience</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/building-an-online-audience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 12:27:38 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/building-an-online-audience/</guid>
      <description>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit. Quas sit expedita, iusto repellendus cumque, officia architecto consequatur illo fuga eum sed ut autem eos voluptas. Nemo, a, rem! Atque quisquam aperiam eaque tenetur autem, soluta itaque omnis. Minus nesciunt, sint, animi illum quo ab voluptate esse delectus unde maiores iure, quasi a suscipit ipsam aliquid voluptatem. Perspiciatis eveniet, pariatur illum aut cum dolor neque consequatur error aliquid facilis in quasi temporibus assumenda tempore, doloremque autem saepe enim nihil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space Shouldn&#39;t Be the Final Frontier</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/space-shouldnt-be-the-final-frontier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 12:21:58 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/space-shouldnt-be-the-final-frontier/</guid>
      <description>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit. Quas sit expedita, iusto repellendus cumque, officia architecto consequatur illo fuga eum sed ut autem eos voluptas. Nemo, a, rem! Atque quisquam aperiam eaque tenetur autem, soluta itaque omnis. Minus nesciunt, sint, animi illum quo ab voluptate esse delectus unde maiores iure, quasi a suscipit ipsam aliquid voluptatem. Perspiciatis eveniet, pariatur illum aut cum dolor neque consequatur error aliquid facilis in quasi temporibus assumenda tempore, doloremque autem saepe enim nihil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Setup Timer Hugo</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 12:22:40 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/installation/</guid>
      <description>Install this template by following those simple steps: STEP-1 : Hugo installation Check this link below for install hugo on your computer. hugo install documentation
STEP-2 : Create your project Hugo provides a new command to create a new website.
hugo new site &amp;lt;new_project&amp;gt; STEP-3 : Install the theme Run this command
hugo new site timer-hugo and then go to the themes folder inside of timer-hugo folder. You can also use this command cd timer-hugo/themes for going to this folder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting on January 8, 2021</title>
      <link>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kavinsampath04.github.io/CharitableInvestmentsClub/blog/blog49/</guid>
      <description>Today we officially completed our organization&amp;rsquo;s bylaws and we are now ready to create a bank account under the corporation&amp;rsquo;s name. This is a huge step in the right direction for us as it sets us apart from many other non profit organizations that have been started by other students. In addition to this, we planned out what the next few days will look like in terms of meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
